heartmybackpack.com 2018-12-25

# Privacy Policy - Heart My Backpack

We at HeartMyBackpack.com do not share personal information with third parties nor do we store any information about your visit to this blog other than to analyze and optimize your content and reading experience through the use of cookies.

You can turn off the use of cookies at anytime by changing your specific browser settings.

We are not responsible for republished content from this blog on other blogs or websites without our permission.

We collect information from you when you subscribe to a newsletter through MailerLite, respond to a survey, or otherwise voluntarily enter information on this site.

We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access our website. For example, when you use the site, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the site. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the site, such as links clicked.   _Your information has been anonymized and only is viewed aggregately._

When you post a comment on blog posts you are required to fill in your name and e-mail address. I will never sell or give away this information, nor will I ever sell or give away your e-mail address should you subscribe to my newsletter or contact me for any other reason.

If you subscribed to our newsletter, you will receive our newsletters. You can always unsubscribe by following the link in email or by emailing us.

Should you choose to voluntarily disclose personal information on our site in the comment field, please be aware that that information can be viewed publicly and can be collected and used by third parties without our knowledge. Such activities are beyond the control of this policy.

If you leave a comment, certain information (your name as you provide it) may be publicly visible, however your email address will not be.  We will  **not**  contact you using your email as this goes against GDPR regulations, so if you wish to be contacted by HeartMyBackpack, please contact us directly.   _Please do not request that we contact you in the comments._

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

HeartMyBackpack.com does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately.  We will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

In some instances, we may include affiliate links in posts where we recommend specific products or activities. If you purchase something through one of my affiliate links, we receive a small commission at no extra cost to you.

All of our affiliates are GDPR compliant.

We are a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to Amazon.com and affiliated sites.

We promise that we take data safety seriously and we use your private data only to offer a personalized experience.

We may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by the website. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the website.

We use cookies to track analytics as well to personalize ads. Cookie data is shared with our advertising company, Mediavine, which serves content and advertisements while you visit the website.

The Website uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads, customize Website content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. Cookies may also be used by third-party services, such as Google Analytics, as described herein.

Users may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies, by the Website, by using a corresponding setting of your internet browser and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. However, if users deactivate the setting of cookies in your Internet browser, not all functions of our Website may be entirely usable.

We may share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information.  Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies.

####  _HeartMyBackpack.com currently uses the following third-party service providers:_

Google Analytics – this service tracks website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the website. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics.  We have anonymized our Google Analytics data and  **never**  look at non-aggregated data.

MailerLite – this service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. We store your email address for purposes of delivering such communications.  Please refer to MailerLite’s privacy policy for further information.

Please be aware that we do not claim any responsibility for the privacy practices of other sites linked to on this website.

HeartMyBackpack.com abides by GDPR regulations, so if you wish to have your information (e.g. comments removed) and you’re an EU resident, please get in touch with us.  We are happy to amend/remove your information/comments/email from the mailing list if you contact us.  We do not retain secondary copies of commenters/reader contact information without permission.  Similarly, we do not resell or share your contact information with third parties.   Similarly, once you opt out of the mailing list, you are  _permanently_  removed.

 **You have the right to:**  

  * be informed regarding how the data is collected and used/li] [li]have access to the data concerning you
  * ask us to change the data about you
  * ask us to delete the data about you
  * ask us to stop sending your newsletters

This privacy policy is subject to change without notice and was last updated on May 2018. If you have any questions feel free to contact me directly at heartmybackpack@gmail.com
